morning
welcome to meditating with Chandra Vicky
I'm a cognitive psychologist and a
cognitive scientist at the university
product by scientifically in
academically study phenomena like
mindfulness and related phenomena like
Insight flow mystical experiences higher
states of consciousness awakening
experiences the cultivation of wisdom
I've also been practicing the pasta
meditation meta contemplation and Tai
Chi Chuan for over twenty nine years and
I've been teaching them professionally
for close to 20 years welcome this is
actually a course if you're joining us
for the first time you're welcome but
I'll be teaching today every Monday is
the Dharma day and this will be the
seventh lesson that I'm teaching if you
want to you can go to the notes in this
video and you'll find links to the
previous sits and the previous lessons
Tuesday through Friday we meet together
again at 9:30 we sit sometimes I review
the principle and the practices that I
did on discussed on Dharma day and then
there's Q&A at the end
in fact on every day through Monday
Monday through Friday there's a Q&A
period at the end for that Q&A period
please limit your questions to this
practice if you have more general
questions about perhaps how this relates
to other wisdom traditions or about my
my videos or my series awakening from
the meaning crisis or voices with
reveille key once a month we have a
general livestream Q&A that you'd be
welcome to join us on so I think that's
everything that I need to announce for
now I hope you're all doing well we're
getting into the part now where we're
having to it's gone from the sprint to
the marathon and this is where having
cultivated deeper inner resources and a
capacity to resilient ly get into the
right relationship with ourselves with
each other in the end
whilst will stand us in good stead
throughout this all right
so please get yourself in a comfortable
position and because I'm gonna do a
fairly long lesson and then we'll say
okay so we've been doing the five
factors of inquiring mindfulness knows
our vigilance which is the core one and
the other one's modified acuity sort of
sensitivity acute acuity noticing and
reminder so we've been doing the
meditative question hopefully to get a
sense of what vigilance is it's that's
watchfulness
it's that exploratory observation it's
trying to get below the surface of the
pond for deep insight the past enough so
we can enhance that by bringing the
other factors into play how do we bring
them into plant how do we practice them
well this is where we're going to be
taking another step forward because what
you're now going to do is you're going
to go from you're going to go beyond
labeling your structions to actually
meditating on your destructions okay so
first of all a very important principle
for this it's very tempting when I teach
people this that they start looking for
their distractions which means they make
themselves more distracted it's like
they give their monkey months and so
meth or something so don't go looking
for distractions I know it's tempting
and you know don't beat yourself up
maybe do but this is the important
principle if you're not practicing this
by trying to provoke distractions I
think it's very important that you allow
them to arise spontaneously if they even
do it all and you really keep your focus
on unfriending yourself and following
your breath but when a distraction
arises we apply the five factors of an
alluring mindfulness well let's go
through them and we'll do it I'll do it
for three kinds of distractions physical
distractions emotional distractions and
mental destructions okay so let's say
there's a physical destruction so one
that people of course commonly have are
all related and anecdote to that about
this you I think it's some kind of pain
in their lives so let's go through it
I got a pain in my leg so what do I do
well first of all I don't stop believin
I always label I step back and label it
then ing word painting normally you
would just here return to your breath
but here's the idea you're just you can
actually put friend your distractions
they're an important arena at which you
can train mindfulness because you're
just fractions often represent very
automatic and ingrained patterns of
behavior so what I'll do is after I've
labeled it I then do vigilance what does
that mean I take an attitude towards it
that I really don't know what this is
completely I don't except the
familiarity as being a complete
revelation of the phenomenon I do not
expect I do not write interpret like I
should say the familiarity I do not
frame it as the familiarity is
equivalent to me having an expertise or
a complete understanding of this
phenomena a complete awareness of it
okay it has not been fully disclosed to
me just because I find it familiar so
this is the sort of enacted humility
that's about right
trying to get below the familiar face of
your experience you apply vigilance that
exploratory observation into the pain
you're gonna say I'm not gonna like that
that's exactly right that's exactly
right but what you can see is that not
liking isn't as devastating as it might
you know have been habituated in you so
I started to think that platoon of
watchfulness of exploration of wanting
to see more thing to learn and more not
wanting to feel good or feel better but
to learn more to learn more okay so then
I moved to sensitivity sensitivity is
turn all of the nouns in Europe mind
into hers this isn't pain it's painting
it's a constantly shifting unfolding
process so sensitivity says go from
taking a snapshot of your experience
that you know and you put into your
memories I picked I know there's
infinitely little there yes go from that
to an exploratory movie
it's unfolding and you're seeing how
it's going to arrest next flowing acuity
acuity so think when I take my glasses
off I lose acuity right everything fuses
together
it's perceptual con fusion fusing
together confused right
everything is confused together and in
order to have a more intelligible
understanding of things I have to be
able to discern and discriminate
that's acuity that's visual acuity you
want to bring it here so you've probably
got this blob of an experience it's all
fused together acuity is pull it apart
and you've been practicing this you've
got the preliminary skill for this
because you've been learning how to find
your clothes so try to notice all the
different kinds of sensations
so you'll notice weight what I was
lumping together is pain some of that is
just tension and then some of that right
some of that is tightness and some of
that is maybe sort of tingling and then
there's this sort of felt nastiness but
it's not as big as I sort of thought it
was and it's really hard to put my mind
on that and there's great a lot of stuff
happening there there's a lot of
different kinds of sensations acuity and
how a lot of things are all fused
together as pain right but once you make
it painting and let it unfold
you can then notice all the different
things and this is how you start to
bring clarity to your awareness you
start to uh them you start to get
discernment and discrimination okay
notice it so vigilance take that
exploratory attitude humility
sensitivity turn it into a flowing verb
not a snapshot now acuity defuse it pull
it all apart right notice all the
different kinds of sensations are the
way they're layered and shifting and
moving around then notice it noticing is
to try to pay attention to the three
kinds of reactions your habit what's
your physical reaction how is the rest
of your body your
energetic felt body reacting to this is
it tightening is it do you feel it
trying to pull away if you feel a part
of it though that's kind of a rule I
don't know but what is your energetic
right here lived body doing with respect
to this your emotional reaction what's
your emotional reaction to this I hate
it I'm angry at it it's unjust maybe but
maybe also yeah I kind of like it a bit
too it sort of gives me a sense of
urgency or connectedness maybe I don't
know I'm not accusing anybody being a
masochist I'm trying to tell you why
that example is you might be you might
be sort of surprised right whoa there's
a lot of complex emotional reaction
going on to this all right sort of all
fused and treated it all at once as a I
don't like it but I'm actually it's a
really complex set of physiological
energetic and emotional reactions
finally mental reaction what's your mind
doing is your mind trying to I want to
go away from this I want to know I want
to make this go away with the raw power
of my will oh I'm going to set this as
the villain and I'm like what is your
mind doing how's it reacting to it so
moving away moving towards it grasping
at trying to shred it try to make it go
away trying to attach to it what is you
mind doing vigilance that exploratory
observation that you've been trained the
core of it sensitivity unfolding it as a
movie acuity pulling it apart into all
the different kinds of sensations
noticing noticing the three reactions
the bodily reaction the emotional
reaction the mental reaction fifth one
reminding what's remaining that's the
core sake stay in mindfulness stay in
mindfulness stay in mindfulness because
as you unpack this you want to make
inferences you want to make
justifications you want to make
explanations you want to tell them
stories keep going back
to vigilance sensitivity acuity noticing
that's what reminding is okay now let's
say you're doing this so let's go back
to my anecdotal example right when I was
first taught this I thought oh this is
great
because I when I was sitting I was
learning
we were sitting for an hour in for a
novice that's a long time right and so
it's really burning in my legs and it
was really a big challenge I'm gonna
talk when I thought about this oh this
is great because you know I was held as
a novice I'm struggling between monkey
mind and you know this turning in my
legs it's like ah this will give me a
focus I'm not a masochist either but the
idea that if pain is such a compelling
it's such a Darwinian primitive
primordial thing that'll keep my
attention for sure that'll keep my
attention for sure so of course I tried
to follow the instructions I didn't look
for my distraction but eventually it did
come up because I was sitting so long I
was it I thought I turned and I started
to apply the five five years of applying
mindfulness and I thought oh I'm going
to be like a laser concentration surely
this will hook my mind and hold my
attention and within about 20 seconds I
was off into monkey month and this
wasn't minor pain I'm talking about was
off and I remember it's such a shocking
experiences oh my gosh
even this my monkey mind blow away so
here's the first principle if while
you're meditating on your distraction
you're distracted from it you go back to
your breath you just go back to very
basic the plasma or meta if you're doing
meta at the time okay so the first
principle is if you go away you return
to the breath if you go where you
returned the breath and then you say
well then my distraction might get me
again my pain in my leg yep and then you
do this and you go where you return to
your breath okay but that takes me to
the next two principles okay here's the
second one this also happened to me pain
came up I was able to stay with it
longer as a practice
and then it went away as I meditated on
it and this is the more tempting thing
because it's like oh oh I could make
everything unpleasant go away with the
power that this is giving me this
meditative power I could make all my
unpleasant sensations go away I could
dissolve away any unpleasant memories
you have to turn away from that Metanoia
turning away from it
the temptation to pursue magic must be
abandoned because it is it is the
greatest fraudulent surrogate for the
cultivation of wisdom so if it goes away
leave this let go of what's happening
and return to your breath return to your
breath of friending and being centered
again and let go of that temptation to
inflation so you go away return to the
breath if it goes away return to your
breath paying very careful attention to
recenter your attitude what's the third
the third is my it doesn't go away you
don't go away or it doesn't go away and
you keep coming back to it again and
again and again okay so this is the
principle of it this is the third and
this is the principle I've been teaching
you through this always is education if
it becomes mere endurance stop so if you
don't go away and it doesn't go away
your sphere like that or it's like yeah
okay stop all right first of all try to
mindfully do this make whatever
adjustment or movement you need to do to
alleviate
the destruction this is the most 10
thing one of all in some ways I mean the
the second one is tempting existentially
this is sort of immediately tempting
because you have to be really honest
with yourself it's like no no I really
am it's just overwhelming me it's just
overwhelming to practice I'm merely
enduring then right return to make at
the adjustments you need to try and
alleviate the distraction and then start
your meditation all over again
separating learning faster if you can
because you're your closer to the
meditative state
okay so let's review for that everything
and then I'll talk about emotional and
mental okay so it comes up and what do I
do I apply the I label it as always that
never stops then I apply the five
factors of in quiet mindfulness and
vigilance looking into it
sensitivity letting it flow acuity
diffusing it noticing my three kinds of
reactions my lived body emotional mental
reminding staying in the practice three
things three principles if I go away I
return to the breath if it goes away I
returned to the breath paying very
careful attention to my attitude if
neither one of us goes away or just
keeps hooking me again and again and
again and again and again I just need to
draw endurance there's no education
happening then I come out of it I make
the adjustments I break it I do what I
need to try and alleviate it and then I
go back into my meditation so that's
right that's physical distractions
emotions so some of you mentioned very
powerful emotions come up first step
back and label the emotion then what
vigilance and here's the thing about
vigilance right vigilance is designed to
get you from just how do I put this
passively undergoing your emotions to
actively exploring that this is shift
and it's sort of subtle until you get it
once you
it's a big shift okay normally we are
sort of looking through emotions like it
when I'm angry I'm sorry I'm sort of
looking angrily and I'm only dimly aware
of my anger and what I want to do is
instead is I want to become very aware
of my anger and look into it deeply or
my sadness sensitivity e-motion
eat motion it's moving it's unfolding
follow it let it flow right acuity
notice expanding your awareness and rich
in your aware to see how everything is
now ready keep gathering back what
you've already learned unfolding it
exploring it diffusing it pulling up all
the kinds of things and what she'll
notice frequently is you're not having a
single emotion this is at the core of
what's called emotion focused therapy
one of the one of the very good evidence
base forms of therapy that underneath
the sadness might be anger and
underneath the anger might be some fear
or underneath the fear might be the
desire for right being special I don't
know what it is I'm this is not any kind
of nyssa necessary sequence I'm giving
you but what you can find very often is
that there is a tremendous layer and
then try to distinguish between the raw
feeling of the emotion and then what it
seems to be wanting to in tell you to do
there's sort of the raw feel like that
the tingly sensations of sadness where
is it in your chest really feel it
really really not right get into the
feeling but then also what is it trying
to what is it trying to say to you what
is it trying to tell you to do okay
notice it so so what's your body where
is it in your body how is your body an
option so in this way let's flip the
order a little bit body what's the mind
doing to the emotion I love this emotion
you'll have a you'll have this
reflective mental judgment and
evaluation of your mode trying to just
notice that notice it
and then you say but what's right and
sometimes you'll have emotions about
your emotions but what you can do for
when you're trying to get is try to take
a meta stance towards your emotion try
to befriend your emotion trying to do
matter towards it try to take that
attitude that you're gonna unlock
towards it and let it unlocked what you
try to befriend the emotion but and it's
very difficult with emotion the the
fifth factor reminding stay in the
practice stay in the practice stay in
the practice same very principles you'll
go away return to the breath it goes
away return to your breath pay attention
to your attitude right and if you're
merely enduring open your eyes shake it
out
let it go re-engage with the practice
basic for passing out or basic matter
okay third thing mental destruction
talking to yourself or running pictures
this is the hardest thinking is a paper
tiger if you can meditate on it
why don't you things are hopping and
getting the space between them is the
initial difficult task one of the things
is you'll turn to meditate on your
thinking and over those disappear it's
gone I try to notice what that feels
like what it's what is it like when
thinking is absent or you'll turn to try
meditator and you'll find yourself
thinking then you're just in the
distraction and then don't do anything
else other than return to your breath
label their thinking go back to your
breath but if the first time thinking
comes up step back there's two primary
ways of thinking right and they often
come together but you can separate them
at least initially in practice the first
one is inner speech here's the thing to
do with inner speech you're talking to
yourself okay don't pay attention to
what is being said pay attention to
quint ease of the voice that is saying
first of all it is your visit your voice
I taught this practiced I have this very
clear memory of teaching this but just
to somebody and he was sort of going
along and he wasn't getting much but
then I taught him this and then he came
back the next week and he was deeply
enthusiastic he said I realized that my
monkey mind was speaking often in my
father's voice not my voice
whose voices are whose voice is it and
if it's your voice when your voice now
is an adult
your voice is a teenager your voice is a
child your voice your older is it a wise
sounding voice
a foolish sounding place does it does it
try to pretend that it has authority or
does it just seem to naturally have
authority over you is it talking quickly
is there an emotional tone to it
imagine you were sitting on a bus next
to somebody speaking a language you
don't understand so you don't know what
they're talking about but you could pick
up all of this kind of information do
that with the voice okay this is a way
of and what and when you do that what
will happening is very soon the thinking
will disappear and note that what's it
like when my mind is empty thought and
then returned to the breath what about
scenes pictures behave as if you are an
art critic in a museum look at this
painting look at these colors look at
the colors look at where they are look
at the texture look at how rapidly or
slowly things are changing notice that
when you are imagining something you're
not actually seeing the whole your oh
there's a tiger is it a whole tiger it's
just sort of part of a tiger's face
right again you're trying to step back
and look at the medium rather than the
meaning of it so there's and again the
three principles it goes away
when it goes away though first notice
that what's it like you go away like it
if you're distracted from your
distraction you just return to the
breath right this one you don't really
get the endurance you might if you're
getting sort of into deep rumination and
then that that's something where I
recommend you don't do this practice to
if you're caught up in like a really
powerful luminate of cycle or right just
do the basic following the breath
okay one more thing so they'll tell you
work with distractions distractions or
things that come up in the practice I
did say this would be a long lesson this
is a really important lesson this is a
transitional lesson we're moving it to a
whole another stage you also need to
deal with hindrances hindrances are the
things that are sort of preventing you
from doing the practice okay there's two
kinds of hindrance there is sort of an
active one you you want to sit you're
bidding this no no no if that's because
of trauma or you're in therapy and
please talk to your therapist about that
but for many of us that's just so that's
just all of the you know the strength of
ego familiarity don't not wanting to
change here's the thing to do you're
already meditating this is the trick
what what do you mean when the
resistance comes up you're already
meditating how apply the five factors of
acquiring mindfulness to it and it'll
either dis exist dissipate and you'll go
breath right you'll go away in which you
returned to the breath and you start
meditating or you start enduring and
then you can just at some point okay I'm
just going to stay with it and I'm gonna
more gently right see if I can turn it
into I'm not enduring I'm just learning
from it
I keep applying the five five years of
acquired mindfulness almost always
you'll find that you can that just get
into the practice that's active
resistance passive resistance it's like
this you go to meditate you go yeah I
should meditate you know should meditate
yeah yeah I mean people have some tea
it's your your motivation just sort of
dissipates away okay and this is a this
is a more insidious kind of hindrance
how do we deal with that so here's where
we take right what are called the three
refuges the Buddha the Dharma an
assignment the Buddha doesn't mean the
historical growth although learning
about the historical Buddha could be
helpful in this it might be might be for
you taking refuge in the Christ it might
be taking refuge in Socrates of your
story okay might be taking refuge in
right love say right if you're Dallas
okay basically taking refuge in your
sage what does that mean taking refuge
in the beam of Buddha means through
your day keep a journal note moments of
when you have been mindful note moments
of when you have seen through allusion
note moments when you have let go of a
habitual pattern this is called water in
your Buddha note those moments and keep
them right so building up a journal of
that builds up your inner teacher your
inner sage and as your Interstates
starts to grow in you it becomes a
palpable presence that helps motivate
you and keep you going
it's basically your future self that is
you're giving birth to the Dharma
this is Dharma when I teach it okay so
for those of you are interested I'm
working on revising our you can have an
older draft of a meditation and
contemplation journal I've written and
there's books at the end that you can
read and I can recommend some books so
wait a little bit longer not because I'm
trying to censor you but it's good to
not get confused but then you want to
start meeting books about mindfulness
perhaps you're interested in the more
philosophical citing of this maybe you
want to set it into a Buddhist Center
maybe you want to set it there's lots of
great Christian meditation of your
Christian if you're stoic and I'm gonna
later I'll be teaching you what would it
be like to engage in stoic Neoplatonic
practices okay so buddha the dharma
learning learning the sangha this is
Sonja meeting with other people meeting
with other people so you regularly
coming here really helps you to keep
meditating and we'll try to keep this I
mean this is a ten week course and
tomorrow and I are talking about what
we're gonna do to keep the like some way
we're footing this thing I keep it going
after this we'll see okay but you need
to meet what you can do is make an
arrangements made with some of the
people you're meeting it on in the chat
to meet together regular the Buddha the
Dharma assignment okay we're going to do
a shorter sit today because that was a
very long lesson well they're going to
sit for 10 min
today okay well I'm gonna sit for 10
minutes because I still also want to
answer some questions I'm going to
review one more time don't look for your
destructions but when they come up as
always label them with an ing word
notice how that prepares you for
sensitivity right away then I apply
vigilance and sensitivity then acuity
then noticing the three kinds of
reaction and all throughout the fifth
factor reminding staying in the
vigilance staying in the vigilance
staying in the practice I go away return
breath if it goes away I return to the
breath paying attention to my attitude
very carefully just endurance I return
to the breath when I'm doing this I'm
thinking and I think he goes away I take
a moment to notice what it's like when I
have no thought all right everyone
that's a very long lesson but this is a
very important practice you're learning
how to discover a lot about yourself by
friending your distractions
okay so readjust your posture probably
you need to readjust your legs a little
bit loosened up just a little bit right
put your phones on Do Not Disturb
get comfortable we're going to begin
when I say begin again
slowly began to come out of your
practice trying as best you can to
integrate what you cultivated in your
practice with your everyday
consciousness and cognition coming out
of your sit as part of the practice so
some questions here will address some of
them these are from also they were
leftover from the live Q&A we had on
Friday this is from a wat your horas I
wonder if you recommend some kind of
emergency meditation in difficult
moments during the day yes the emergency
meditation is to very quickly you will
be able to do it comprehensively try to
this is why you're cultivating it so
in-depth and carefully and slowly on
your set try and find your Center try
and find your root try to feel the flow
right and then try to bring that kind of
inquiring mindfulness and presence of
mind to the situation that you're in so
find the 4 4 and then try to integrate
that into the situation you're in
especially with the 5 factors of
employing mindfulness you won't get into
a deeply that's not the point the point
is you've trained all of this transfer
your training just do the triggering
that will transfer the training the
triggering that will transfer the
training the triggering that will
transfer the training center rudik flow
it focusing car and mindfulness back to
the first one as I mentioned if you're
distracted from your distraction it's up
the TS Eliot line my distraction from
just distracted from our distractions by
distractions right if you're distracted
from your distraction you've gone away
from the original instruction returned
your breath you let the whole you know
that's the whole process of medicating
all your distractions go and you just
return to your breath right always
return to your breath and then continue
on with the past
we'll go back into meta mr. Onur
what about finding your flow in arms
legs and head part of me wants to be
aware of the body sensation of the
extremity - you can you can't the reason
why we leave the mode is it's often hard
to you notice them being moved by the
breath that's one thing and our arms and
our legs seem to be not for everybody
but for many people they seem to be
particularly distracting I guess because
arms and legs are so involved with a lot
of our actions and our narratives and
our projects and gestures right so
here's the thing
extend to flow into your arms and legs
as you want if right you if that is not
causing us an upsurge in your monkey
mind and if you can do if that if that
happens then I would say remain with the
torso but if you say no no it just
enhances I stay more present right and I
could feel the circulation I can feel
the effect of my breath in my legs my
arms and by all means extend it that way
he's like I said I usually hold off with
people at novices because it seems to be
either on one end it's very difficult
for people to pick up on the motions
because their legs tend to be fixed the
arms tend to be much more stable but if
you can that's great but also you want
to get in between I can't find it or I'm
just going to monkey mind if you can get
that place the by all means do so these
if Lisa Carlucci when rooting the right
side of my body isn't include in the
process it's like it's in the dark I
have to consciously include it over and
over again what does that mean
well a lot of us will find it's but it's
lateralized tends to indicate that we're
tend to be lateralized in our bodies and
in some way this is probably part of
that body honor I was talking about
earlier and interesting the right side
of the body as the left hemisphere and
that tends to be sort of it can be much
more about you know a step by step very
formal language based way of thinking
and that that can get us out of our body
so it's very
it's very good to try and keep opening
up the right side of your body it will
change the time right I've been at the
left side of my body has taken a very
very long time to open up because of you
I think you're I mean we know that
people are on a continuum in terms of
sort of the degree to which they have
left or right hemispheric dominance I
see some of the work of Ian evoke
restore some of my lectures on this
right and so shifting that I can take
quite a bit of time it's taken me years
and years to you know for the left side
of my body to gradually wake up so that
is normal I think that's what's
happening and I can encourage you from
my own experience at the expense of
others that you can definitely make
progress on this shine a list I find
what I'm distraction as soon as I bring
in the ing word it naturally disappears
and my impulse is to go back to the
breath exactly trying to bring the five
factors of mindfulness feels like I'm
grasping onto the distraction should I
only do this practice when it's released
or in distraction yes if that's what I
meant by being a paper tiger if when you
do the ing thing it disappears then
return to your breath if you're doing a
myth if it's a mental thing like
thinking of right and it disappears
notice where it's liked notice what that
moment feels like tastes like in your
mind and also when doing that pay very
careful attention to your attitude
you're not trying to build up a habit of
being becoming a magician that you're
doing - ooh got my mental powers so
that's what you do in that situation
Raoh ruled your auras has asked another
question I tend to be very excited when
the practice actually works the next day
it becomes hard to do it again because
of an underlying false belief that I've
mastered it and you can do it whenever I
like help okay so that's that's what I
mean
that's we're dealing with the B you know
this is a hindrance this is we're
bringing in the three jewels cultivating
the lived sense of the presence of the
Buddha learn one
things about learning is it will really
help you realize you're not a master
learn a lot more Sangha meet and talk to
other people they both help you they
these things all help us from getting
discouraged because I can never do it
and getting inflated because I always
know I was a Buddha the three jewels the
three refuges keep us in that middle
path between those two okay we have some
questions that are left over we're going
to deal with them tomorrow because I've
already taken up a lot of your time so I
want to thank you for joining I want to
thank my dear friend of techno mage
Amara my beloved son Jason please
subscribe to this channel to be notified
of the next video again you can go to
links in this video to find previous
lessons and sets you can also get links
to my channel where you'll find the
videos on all of these phenomena and I
were talking about like mindfulness and
flow and insight and mystical experience
higher states of consciousness
transformative experience the
cultivation of wisdom responding to the
meaning crisis that's at work in our
culture at large please invite others to
this practice for my benefit from it you
could help me extend how I'm helping
others if you invite other people up to
it remember we're doing this every
weekday 9:30 est Monday is Dharma day
Tuesday through Friday our sit days
thank you very much everybody for your
time and attention take care keep up the
practice and I'll see you all tomorrow